Fraser Molyneux – MX Consulting

Mobile: 07725111939

Email Address: molyneux-consulting-ltd@outlook.com

Website: https://www.mx-consulting.co.uk

Blog: https://molyneux.me GitHub: https://github.com/frasermolyneux

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fraser-molyneux

I am currently in a contract consulting on transforming development capability and release management in the aerospace/defence sector. Available from April 5th for outside-IR35 roles.

I am a Lead Software Engineer with experience of supporting business critical services and delivering project work. Skilled in the development and implementation of deployment pipelines using PowerShell, DSC and Azure DevOps. Security conscious and a certified ethical hacker. C#.NET, Web API, ASP.NET, Azure software engineer. I currently hold active security clearance.

Key Skills

- C#.NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- .NET Core
- Web API
- PowerShell/DSC/Pester
- Git/GitHub/Azure DevOps
- Build & Release through Azure DevOps CI/CD Pipelines
- Azure/AWS
- SQL Server/Entity Framework
- Agile/Scrum
- Release Management

Education

I hold the following professional qualifications:

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Web Applications
- Microsoft Specialist Programming in C#
- Certified Ethical Hacker (EC-Council)
- Xamarin Certified Mobile Developer
- Professional Scrum Developer I
- ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

I hold the following academic qualifications:

- BSc Computer Science University of South Wales 1st Degree with Honours
- HND Computing University of Glamorgan Distinction
- I also have 'A' level qualifications in Engineering and Computing and 9 GCSE's grades A to C including English Language and Maths.

Work Experience – MX Consulting (Molyneux Consulting Ltd)

I have recently made the move from permanent to working as a personal services company, this has allowed me to focus using my expertise in delivery targeted value to my clients.

Software Engineering Consultant – From Nov 2019 to present I have been working on a contract to deliver a development capability for a client in the aerospace/defence sector. This has involved the introduction of an Agile way of working, DevOps principles and CI/CD principles.

I have been working with a team of established developers/testers and brownfield products to adapt and change to support the changing direction of the business to deliver data driven decisions.

Additionally, for this contract I have been using my experience and expertise in CI/CD pipelines to improve the existing delivery pipelines (in Team City) and practices around release management.

Work Experience – UK Hydrographic Office

The UK Hydrographic Office (UKHO) is a world-leading centre for hydrography, specialising in marine geospatial data that helps others to unlock a deeper understanding of the world's oceans. It is a Ministry of Defence trading fund and generates a £151 million turnover. Its products are on over 90% of commercial vessels.

I have held several roles in the organisation working up from an entry level trainee software engineer to leading my own team responsible for developing and supporting business critical SOLAS (safety of live at sea) services.

Lead Software/Support Engineer – From July 2018 to Nov 2019 I have been leading an Agile (Scrum) development team of 5 developers and 2 testers which support the UKHO customer facing services and delivers project work.

The core skills/technologies used in this role have been:

- C#.NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- PowerShell/DSC/Pester
- PowerShell Modules
- SQL Server
- Azure
- Git/GitHub/Azure DevOps
- ITIL/Incident/Change

Some of my notable achievements in this role have been:

I have recently led on a large a project to migrate the UKHO customer facing services from our old data centre running VMWare to our new one on Hyper-V. This involved major rewrites of build and release pipelines, tackling large technical debt and challenges in implementing new technologies, processes and standards.

Introduction of PowerShell infrastructure automated tests that monitor active directory, file share permissions, SQL databases/permissions. These Pester tests have provided confidence and assurance of our service infrastructure and security.

Creation of a route-to-live pipeline for the 'eNavigator Fleet Manager' product that enables easy nodowntime releases speeding up the delivery of project work and allowing a true move towards continuous delivery.

Senior Software Engineer – From September 2017 to July 2018. For this role I worked on multiple projects for both desktop and web applications as well as working on the migration of the UKHO customer facing services from our old data centre running VMWare to our new one on Hyper-V.

The desktop and web project technologies focused around:

- C#.NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- Web API
- Automated Testing (Selenium)
- Unit Testing

The majority of the data centre migration work entailed creating deployment pipelines and working closely with an embedded Operations engineer to integrate the solutions into the new architecture.

The pipelines were created using TFS for build and release orchestration with PowerShell and PowerShell DSC used to execute the deployment onto VMs. The technologies were around:

- PowerShell/DSC/Pester
- Azure DevOps/vNext
- Active Directory Management
- Build/Release through TFS
- NVD Security Checking
- Forti-ADC (Load balancing) Configuration
- Networking
- SQL Server
- Azure/ARM

Software Engineer – From July 2016 to September 2017. For this role I was part of a desktop and mobile apps team.

The projects worked on primarily used the following technologies:

- C#.NET
- WPF
- Xamarin
- PowerShell (Automated Test Deployment)
- Automated Testing (CodedUi/Xamarin.UITest)
- Unit Testing/TDD

As part of my work in Xamarin I created a shared automated test library for both Xamarin. Andriod and Xamarin. IOS. The library was used to reduce the amount of duplicated code.

Trainee Software Engineer – From November 2015 to July 2016. The UKHO has a fantastic trainee programme that incorporates solo and group working to develop skills, confidence and good practice.

Whilst a trainee I worked with my mentor and peers to gain a good knowledge of enterprise software development processes and practices.

There is a focus on learning the best practices and with my mentor I developed my experience of:

- C#, .NET, ASP.NET MVC, WPF, SQL Server Development Stack
- Unit testing, automated tests, selenium Testing processes
- Agile, Scrum Development approach

Towards the end of my trainee programme I integrated with an agile development team that was working with WPF for a desktop application. I gained a good understanding of the business domain and was able to contribute to the production code.

Work Experience – Other

Workshop Delivery Officer - From October 2014 to May 2015 I was employed by the University of South Wales as an hourly paid lecturer. I was responsible for delivering lessons on behalf of Technocamps to many schools in South Wales. The taught subjects were on Python, Greenfoot (Java), the use of Raspberry Pi's and other educational technologies. I was responsible for delivering set lessons and creating lesson plans.

Interests

From a young age, I have had an interest in gaming which over time evolved into a passion for programming and server management. For the past ten years, I have managed the infrastructure of an online gaming community which has now expanded to over 30 game servers; 10,000 members and a forum with 750,000 posts. I manage the core infrastructure, networking, websites and server migrations as well as shaping the community's expansion.

I am a keen traveller and enjoy experiencing other cultures; having taken long trips to both Japan and Ghana my communication skills have increased, as has my knowledge of the different nations.

In 2013 I spent six weeks volunteering in Ghana - Africa. I was involved in a construction programme for a school as well as taking part in teaching the children new skills. I taught lessons in English, ICT and other subjects as well as helping the local teachers.

My preference for logical and object orientated programming languages has allowed me to create many personal programming projects to solve a variety of issues.

References

Both academic and professional references can be supplied on request.